Okay, so Minneapolis, I mean that slogan just
demanded to be born.
So this was created after the police murder of Jamar Clark.
Somebody I haven't been able to track down the photographer posted a photograph
taken at these protests, which were in North Minneapolis,
another young man murdered by the police in 2015 or 2016.
And that was the photograph of the heavily armed cop on the top of one of their
vehicles, right, of this protest, that this peaceful protest.
And the I found the the photographs striking and added the subtext.
The message, I think, really where the deepest meaning is is in the sub title,
this is protecting wealth and whiteness in 1867.
So again, that's another example of wanting to contribute some into the conversation that isn't there.
This poster doesn't say cops bad people good.
This poster says this institution of the police has a particular historical origin,
grounding and purpose.
And that's the statement that I felt needed to be made.
And interestingly enough, that was on the wall of my shop and sparked a conversation that led to the creation of MPD 150,
the local police abolition organization grassroots organization that created a
people's performance review because it said 1867.
This was in 2016.
We looked at that poster and said 2016 1867 ends in a seven day.
Next year, it's going to be the 150th anniversary of the Minneapolis Police Department that puts the two years after emancipation a few years after the Dakota rebellion here in Minnesota.
And nobody's ever written a history of the MPD.
Nobody certainly has written a performance review.
So let's look at them and see if they should be reupped for the next 150 years.
How are they doing in that producer report and produced an exhibit and scenes and school curricula and audio book and many other things that helped lay the groundwork for a shift in the conversation.
You know, at the conference that you attended, Michelle, remember being on that panel and saying, you know, one of our goals as MPD 150 is to shift the political chemistry so that nobody can have a radio conversation or TV or media or academic conversation about the police without the word abolition being part of the conversation.
And that was actually achieved years earlier than we thought it would be.
And then of course, when George Floyd was murdered, in fact, MPD 150 was about to sunset out at that point.
So ourselves is having a limited mission and a limited time span.
And then when it was as though we had planted dandelion seeds in a field where a tornado struck.
And all of a sudden we were getting phone calls from Rio de Janeiro and Istanbul and all over the world asking what is this abolition stuff you all are talking about.
And we created a triage system with two of the other groups here.
Reclaim the block any phone calls coming in about policy would go to them phone calls coming in about community organizing would go to the black visions collective.
You know, interview requests, whatever coming in asking about abolition would come to us.
Because there was, you know, was just nobody had the capacity to handle it all.
But anyway, that's some sort of the way this particular seed happens to be located right at the conversions of, you know, of pressure points of meridians to put it in the dismal terms so that.
And it's true of all of our none of our art is so powerful that it changes history any more than a needle changes the health of the human being.
But if the needle is placed at the right location at the right moment, it can only unleash a tremendous amount of energy or power.
And that's kind of how I view the ways in which when art happens to be at a turning point where it can make something happen.
And again, this didn't fuck a rebellion. It simply helped initiate an idea that started an organization that leads some groundwork that.
And it's down stream was able to be part of a major shift in the political environment.
It's one of the interesting places that we find ourselves and this is true of storytellers of all kind and I include organizers in that category is.
To be present in the moment and be able to also illuminate its connection does the moment.
And that includes the past and the future.
And this poster looks back in the same way that the trade on Martin poster looks both back and forward.
This one just looks forward by implication.
Right.
Like they're right.